<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>Catherine E. CoscaCathy.Cosca@noaa.govSimone R. AlinNOAA Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory7600 Sand Point Way NE  Seattle WA, 98115 USA206-526-6819simone.r.alin at noaa.govCatherine E. CoscaNOAA Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory7600 Sand Point Way NE  Seattle WA, 98115 USA206-526-6183Cathy.Cosca@noaa.govRichard A. FeelyNOAA Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory7600 Sand Point Way NE  Seattle WA, 98115 USA206-526-6214Richard.A.Feely at noaa.govTBDNOAA's Ocean Acidification Program9/30/2015DY1402 (330A20140303)Surface underwayResearch vesselLicor, IncDY1402 West Coast Ocean Acidification Monitoring Network: Volunteer Oserving ShipsBering Sea, Gulf of Alaska, North Pacific Ocean, 179.08-151.74562.39152.8413/3/20148/13/2014Oscar Dyson330ANational Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA)XCO2_WATPPMXCO2_AIRPPMXCO2_AIR_INTERPPPMEQ_PREHPAATM_PREHPAEQ_TMPDEG_CSSTDEG_CSSSSea surface salinityFCO2_WAT_SSTUATMFCO2_AIRUATMDEL_FCO2UATMPCO2_WAT_SSTUATMPCO2_AIRUATMDEL_PCO2UATMGeneral Oceanics 8050.  PMEL system ID: GO9BowShower headabout 0.5 L3 L/minabout 0.8 L/mVentedFrom Pierrot, et al.:  Sample air is dried in a condenser that is cooled to 4-5 oC by a Peltier thermoelectric
device. This partially dried air flushes a chamber that is vented and remains at
ambient pressure. The dried air inside the chamber is used as the counter flow in the
Nafion tubing. A vacuum pump pulls the dried air from the chamber first through a
fixed restrictor and then through the Nafion tubes, thus creating an absolute
pressure and corresponding partial pressure gradient for water vapor across the
membrane. When atmospheric air is measured, some of the partially dried air (80-
100 ml/min) is pushed through a Nafion tube, the analyzer and out a vent instead of
flushing the chamber.
The headspace gas, when being measured, is circulated in a closed loop through
the analyzer at a rate similar to that of the atmospheric air (80-100 ml/min). It is
dried first in the condenser, then in a Nafion tube prior to entering the analyzer and
being returned to the equilibrator.   Typically, the water mole fraction (xH2O) in the
dried gas is about 2 parts per thousand (ppt), which corresponds to a dew point
temperature of about -20 degrees Celsius.  The liquid water condensed out of the sample air
streams is removed by peristaltic pumps into the vent equilibrator at intervals
determined by the user._no_match_Licor, IncLicor 7000, IRG4-0847_no_match_0.2 uatm0.3 uatm for equilibrator measurements, 0.2 uatm for atmospheric measurements0.2 uatm0.3 uatm for equilibrator measurements, 0.2 uatm for atmospheric measurementsStandard gases are supplied by NOAA's Earth System Research Laboratory, Global Monitoring Division, in Boulder, CO, and are directly traceable to the WMO scale. LL83539, 245.43 ppm;  LL154363, 420.76 ppm; LL108056, 501.998 ppm; LL63968, 659.096 ppm_no_match__no_match_Seabird 45, maintained on the NOAA Ship Oscar Dyson0.0025 degrees CelsiusSeabird 45, maintained on the NOAA Ship Oscar Dyson0.005 PSU_no_match_Pierrot, D.; Neill, C.; Sullivan, K.; Castle, R.; Wanninkhof, R.; Luger, H.; Johannessen, T.; Olsen, A.; Feely, R.A.; and Cosca, C.E. (2009). Recommendations 
   for autonomous underway pCO2 measuring systems and data-reduction routines. Deep-Sea Res., II, v. 56, pp. 512-522.Feely, R.A., R. Wanninkhof, H.B. Milburn, C.E. Cosca, M. Stapp, and P.P. Murphy,  A new automated underway system for making high precision pCO2 measurements 
   onboard research ships, Analytica Chim. Acta, 377, 185-191, 1998.Wanninkhof and Thoning,  Measurement of fugacity of Carbon Dioxide in surface water and air using continuous sampling methods, Marine Chemistry, 44, 189-205, 1993.Alin, Simone R.; Cosca, Catherine E.; Feely, Richard A.; Lebon, Geoffrey T. (2015). Partial pressure of carbon dioxide (pCO2), temperature, salinity 
   and other variables collected from surface underway observations using shower header carbon dioxide equilibrator, carbon dioxide gas detector, and other instruments 
   from R/V Oscar Dyson in the Berling Sea and coast of Alaska from 2014-03-03 to 2014-08-13 (NCEI Accession 0132046). NOAA National Centers for Environmental Information. [access date]_no_match__no_match__no_match__no_match_Surface underway_no_match_